Trevor Martz

trevorlmartz@gmail.com

+64 022 387 0946

Summary

A versatile, hardworking software developer with OOP, functional, front end development, and api design experience. An effective problem-solver who can adapt quickly to changing technologies and environments. A fast learner who enjoys learning new technologies.

Strong preference for frontend work, but a well rounded full stack developer.

Work History

LiveAuctioneers

New Zealand

Lehi, UT - remote

Software Engineer

November 2018 - Present

- Project Lead for building and management of an in house component library using React and Storybook, published via npm.
- Worked on various parts of 2 outwards facing React websites and 1 internal.
- Worked closely with the design team to update and standardize many design elements of the sites.
- Built major parts of the payments processing system in GO.
- Maintained classic php code.
- Unit testing in all above frameworks.

Dealersocket

Software Engineer

March 2016 - November 2018

Draper, UT

- Worked with maintaining a React front end component library and standards
- Built an admin app using React and Redux-saga
- Worked on the ElasticSearch implementation in C# and Angular/Typescript.
- Worked on the Admin section in C# and Angular/Typescript.
- Maintained classic code.
- Unit testing in all above frameworks.

Towers Watson

Intern Developer

Salt Lake City, UT

October 2015 - December 2015

- Used Node utilizing ES6 to build a node-cli tool to do controlled releases to GitHub.
- Used Node utilizing ES6 to build a deployment hook, which would do releases for the company. It would verify that no code has been changed since being approved by QA, and various other things to prevent malicious intent.

MaritzCx

South Jordan, UT

- Worked with ASP.NET MVC4 to build an internal project to allow the company to work more efficiently
- Fixed bugs
- Created new application features

Education

Bachelor of Science Computer Science Neumont University Cumulative GPA 3.6

Graduated March 2016

Other Projects		
Project	Roles & Responsibilities	Date
Open Source work for 3rd party game client A 3rd party client for OSRS called Runelite. Technologies: Java	 Developer Built several small features. Fixed some bugs. 	2020
Discord Bot A discord bot that we used in a server to help organize for gaming. It also had a lot of fun features that people could use. Technologies: Node, hosted in an AWS remote server	Solo Developer • Designed and built the entire bot.	2017-2018
Machine-Learning Stoplights A system that watches traffic patterns and adjusts the stoplights to create optimal travel. Technologies: C++, Freeglut opengl	 Solo Developer City simulation GUI display of simulation Brains Centralized works together Decentralized works alone Genetic 	April 2015 - June 2015
Certain Death A 2D facebook app where the goal is to survive for as long as possible. Technologies: ASP.Net MVC 5, Facebook integration, HTML5, CSS3	 Developer World generation Resource generation Handling player data Creating and storing buildings 	February 2015 - March 2015
Evolution of Defense A top down tower defense game that evolves as you play. Technologies: ASP.Net C#, Monogame, Git	 Developer Various monsters in the game Waves of monsters Placing and functionality of towers In game shop Evolution to future ages 	August 2014 - September 2014
Chess An interactive chess game complete with rules and networking capabilities. Technologies: Java, SVN, Swing	 Solo Developer Models and logic of the game Includes check, checkmate, castling, pawn promotion, and en passant. Peer to peer networking. Interactive GUI. 	May 2014 – June 2014

PROFESSIONAL REFERENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST Last Updated November 15th 2021